Linus Peng

601 Little Lonsdale Street • Melbourne • VIC 3000

Phone (61) 0416-468482 • E-MAIL penxumelb@gmail.com • Website: https://linusmelb.github.io

SUMMARY

Innovative tech mind with 3 years of experience working as a software developer. Capable of working with a variety of technology and software solutions, and managing databases. A valuable team member who has experience diagnosing problems and developing solutions. Talented programmer with unique ideas and a huge passion for learning new things.

EDUCATION The University of Melbourne

Bachelor of Science, Computing and Software Systems

National University of Singapore – 2017.07 - 2017.12

Exchange program, Computer Science (Melbourne Global Scholars Award)

SKILLS Programming languages: Python, Javascript, NodeJS, Java, PHP

> Web Technologies: Vuejs, RESTFul, HTML, CSS, Webpack Web & App Tracking: Google Analytics, GTM, Firebase

Database: MSSQL, Mysql, MongoDB Big Data/Cloud: BigQuery, GCP

Data Visualisation: Tableau, Data Studio

ACHIEVEMENTS Developed a Sell & Buy app that has more than 15000+ users

(Progressive web app on wechat)

2nd Place at Webjet internal secure code tournament

(More than 30+ developers participated including senior devs)

Arranged 20000 medical face masks to help people in Melbourne and

Brisbane during co-vid19

(8000 shipped to Brisbane and 12000 shipped to Melbourne)

EXPERIENCE

Webjet Limited (ASX: WEB), Analytics Developer

2018.11 – Present

- Re-designed and developed a few critical ingestion pipelines to process over 50GB data per day.
- Designed a new algorithm to utilise multithreading to improve ETL performance (2-3 times faster depending on available cores on VM).
- Built an internal portal (Vue.js, Flask and deployed via docker) to monitor ETL processes.
- Replaced single-node Tableau server with multi-nodes architecture to enhance its capability to handle large concurrent requests.
- Led and implemented robust app tracking on both Android and iOS apps, covering the whole purchase funnel and user interactions.
- Applied Google Analytics new measurement protocol to enhance web tracking.
- Worked with Facebook & Criteo's Engineering Team to integrate third party scripts on website to do dynamic remarketing & retargeting

Novatti Group Limited(ASX: NOV), Web developer & SEO developer 2018.07 – 2018.10

- Project link https://www.chinapayments.com
- Integrated Bootstrap4 and ParticleJs into the website to design a brand new UI
- Led and participated in the design, testing, and deployment of application to the cloud
- Helped boost the company's online presence & website traffic

Radio Fodder - University of Melbourne Student Radio, Web developer 2018.01 – 2018.08

- Project link http://www.radiofodder.com
- Redesigned and developed the website based on the requirement
- Integrated an online radio system into the website

MelMel Consulting PTY LTD, Software Developer

2015.06 - 2017.01

- Project link:
 - o http://www.rejoiceworld.com.au
 - http://www.melmel.com.au/service
- Revised programming and software development projects by updating code and working to improve functionality.
- Designed and deployed the WordPress sites for clients